<?xml version='1.0'?>
<questions>
    <question-type>
        <question>What is Malicious Software or Malware?</question>
        <answer>Malicious Software or Malware refers to a program that is inserted into a system, usually covertly, with the intent of compromising the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of the victim’s data, applications, or operating system (OS) or of otherwise annoying or disrupting the victim.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>Name two possible classifications of Malware.</question>
        <answer>1. Propagation: how it spreads or propagates to get to its target(s).
2. Payload: actions it performs once a target is reached.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>List three examples of Malware propagation.</question>
        <answer>1. Infection of executables or interpreted content.
2. Software or OS vulnerability exploits.
3. Social engineering attacks.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>List three examples of Malware payload.</question>
        <answer>1. Corruption of system/data files.
2. Theft of services/information.
3. Stealting.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>Name two other possible classifications besides propagation versus payload.</question>
        <answer>1. Needs a host program (parasitic) versus Independent, self-contained program.
2. Replicating versus Non-Replicating.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>Name three possible sources for attacks.</question>
        <answer>1. Individuals.
2. Organizations.
3. Governments.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are Advanced Persistent Threats (APTs)?</question>
        <answer>Advance: Uses a wide variety of (possibly custom made) intrusion techniques and malware.
Persistent: Application over an extended period of time.
Threats: Often aims selected targets.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What is a computer virus designed to do?</question>
        <answer>A computer virus is designed to self-replicate – make copies of itself – and distribute the copies to other files, programs, or computers, by attaching itself to some existing executable content. Viruses try to disguise and hide their existence.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are the three components of a computer virus?</question>
        <answer>1. Infection mechanism or infection vector: means by which it spreads or propagates.
2. Payload: the code for the virus’s objective.
3. Trigger or logic bomb: a condition that causes the payload to be executed (usually involves user interaction).</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are the four phases of a computer virus?</question>
        <answer>Dormant phase: The virus is idle. (Not all viruses have this stage.)
2. Propagation phase: The virus places a copy of itself into other programs or into certain system areas on the disk. The copy may have morphed.
3. Triggering phase: The virus is activated (possibly due to a variety of system events) to perform the function for which it was intended.
4. Execution phase: The virus function (benign or harmful) is performed. Executions are typically done by an operating system (OS) – compiled viruses, or by an application – interpreted viruses.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are four ways computer viruses can be classified by target?</question>
        <answer>1. Boot sector infector: Infects a master boot record or boot record.
2. File infector: Infects files that the operating system or shell consider to be executable.
3. Macro virus: Infects files with macro or scripting code that is interpreted by an application.
4. Multipartite virus: Infects files in multiple way</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are four ways computer viruses can be classified by concealment strategy?</question>
        <answer>1. Encrypted virus: the virus is encrypted with a different key for each instance, there is no constant bit pattern to observe.
2. Stealth virus: A form of virus explicitly designed to hide itself from detection by anti-virus software.
3. Polymorphic virus: A virus that mutates with every infection, making detection by the signature of the virus impossible.
4. Metamorphic virus: It mutates with every infection by the virus rewriting itself completely at each iteration</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>How can computer viruses avoid detection due to the size change of programs?</question>
        <answer>Computer viruses can remove a portion of the program that is equal to their size before copying themselves over.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are four properties of a Macro or Scripting virus?</question>
        <answer>1. A macro virus is platform independent.
2. Macro viruses infect documents, not executable portions of code.
3. Macro viruses are easily spread.
4. Access controls are of limited use in preventing their spread, since users are expected to modify them.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What are some possible ways that worms can access a remote system and propagate?</question>
        <answer>• Electronic mail or instant messenger facility.
• File sharing.
• Remote execution capability.
• Remote file access or transfer capability.
• Remote login capability.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>Describe the typical propagation phase for a worm.</question>
        <answer>• Search for appropriate access mechanisms to other systems to infect
    – examining host tables, address books, etc.
    – scanning possible target host addresses – random, hit-list, topological,
and local subnet.
    – searching for suitable removable media devices to use.
• Use the access mechanisms found to transfer and run a copy of itself.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>Explain what a Trojan horse is.</question>
        <answer>Trojan horses are non-replicating programs that appear to be benign but actually have a hidden malicious purpose. Some Trojan horses are intended to replace existing files, such as system and application executables, with malicious versions; others add another application to systems instead of overwriting existing files.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What three models do Trojan horses typically fit into?</question>
        <answer>1. Continuing to perform the function of the original program and additionally performing a separate malicious activity.
2. Continuing to perform the function of the original program but modifying the function to perform malicious activity.
3. Performing a malicious function that completely replaces the function of the original program.</answer>
    </question-type>
</questions>