<?xml version='1.0'?>
<questions>
    <question-type>
        <question>List and define the three business sectors.</question>
        <answer>- Primary: Raw resources
            - Secondary: Manufactured products
            - Tertiary: Services/Information</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What is a stakeholder?</question>
        <answer>A person or a company with a vested interest in the success of a company.</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>List common internal stakeholders and their objectives.</question>
        <answer>- General Employee: Earn high wages and keep their jobs
            - Marketing manager: Impact of advertising (marketing campaigns)
            - Company lawyer: Ensure laws are followed
            - Tax manager: Ensure taxes are minimized and tax laws are followed
            - Owners (sole proprietor): Maximize profit, grow/expand the business</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>List common external stakeholders and their objectives.</question>
        <answer>- Shareholders (of a corporation): Decide to invest or not invest, earn income from their investment
            - Governments: Ensure businesses pay taxes, employ more people, follow laws
            - Customers: Buy quality products at low prices, get the best warranties on products or services
            - Suppliers: Sell products/services to the business, get paid on time and in full
            - Creditors (banks): Decide whether to lend money and how much, ensure business repays loan plus interest on time
            - Society/Community: Employ people from the community, improve the standard of living, run their businesses in an ethical manner, reduce/eliminate any negative environmental effects of their business practices, support local charities</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>List the 6 qualitative characteristics.</question>
        <answer>- Faithful
            - Relevant
            - Comparable
            - Verifiable
            - Timely
            - Understandable</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>List the 6 underlying assumptions.</question>
        <answer>- Separate Entity
            - Unit of Measure
            - Going Concern
            - Historic Cost
            - Time Period (Periodicity)
            - Full Disclosure</answer>
    </question-type>
    <question-type>
        <question>What does GAAP stand for, and what does it include?</question>
        <answer>Generally Accepted Accounting Principles, including the qualitative characteristics and underlying assumptions.</answer>
    </question-type>
</questions>